# **Nelly-Charlott Schneider, Frontend Developer**

Berlin, +49 17656816398, nellychschneider@gmail.com LinkedIn, GitHub, Personal website

I am a Intermediate Frontend Web Developer with almost three years of experience working with React, React Native and TypeScript. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set and ready to acquire new skills, I am able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

### **SKILLS**

React. React Native, TypeScript, GraphQL, JavaScript, HTML & CSS, Git & GitHub

### WORK EXPERIENCE

December 2022 – present Frontend Developer at Climaider, Copenhagen

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate front-end features with back-end systems
- Contributed to the development of new features to enhance the user experience on the website
- Assisted with website optimization for improved page load speed and user experience
- Implemented responsive design to ensure optimal viewing experience on various devices

November 2019 – November 2022 Intermediate Software Engineer at Nuri (ex Bitwala), Berlin

- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.
- Working with agile methodologies

April 2022 – May 2022 Frontend Developer at KasparAI, Copenhagen

• Transitioning their Vanilla JavaScript website to ReactJS

## **EDUCATION**

August 2019 – October 2019 Ironhack, Berlin 9-Week Web Development Bootcamp

## Acquired Skills:

- HTML5, CSS3 & Samp; Responsive Web Design
- Fundamentals of Object-oriented programming based on JavaScript
- Integration of third party services (APIs)
- Writing clean, modular and efficient code and develop well-tested applications using TDD (Test Driven Development) principles
- Agile tools and methodologies

## **HOBBIES**

I love being outdoors and being creative. Playing guitar, some banjo and bass, singing, making (sometimes digital) art and video montages of trips.

Recently I started having an interest in VR and the many possibilities of it, so I'm trying to learn more about this technology.

### **LANGUAGES**

German, Native speaker

English, Highly proficient